Yumi A tvN original series
유미 tvN 오리지널 시리즈
Yumi's Cells
유미의 세포
Episode 30 What's wrong, Wung?
30화 무슨 일이야, 웡?
What's wrong?
무슨 일이야?
I am Wung's training cell.
나는 Wung의 훈련실입니다.
I practice saying "What's wrong?" all day long.
"왜 그래?"라고 말하는 연습을 해요. 종일.
What's wrong?
무슨 일이야?
What's wrong? What's—
무슨 일이야? 뭐죠—
But, I don't really know when to use these words.
그런데 이 단어를 언제 사용해야 할지 잘 모르겠습니다.
What's wrong?
무슨 일이야?
It's my duty to learn the tradition that has been passed down and spread it to future generations.
계승되어 온 전통을 배워 후세에 전하는 것이 나의 임무이다.
What's— Damn it!
뭐야- 젠장!
Tradition or whatever. I'm sick of it!
전통이든 뭐든요. 난 지겨워!
What are you doing not practicing?
연습 안 하고 뭐해요?
Master, I want to do something productive like other cells.
스승님, 저도 다른 세포처럼 생산적인 일을 하고 싶습니다.
Not useless things like this.
이런 쓸데없는 일이 아닙니다.
You rascal!
이 악당!
It is also important to train to say "What's wrong".
"무슨 일이야?"라고 말하는 훈련도 중요합니다.
Why aren't you immediately getting back up?
왜 즉시 회복하지 않습니까?
What on earth does "what's wrong" mean?
도대체 "무슨 일이야"은(는) 무슨 뜻인가요?
What's so important about it that I have to train like this?
그게 뭐가 중요해서 이렇게 훈련해야 하는 걸까요?
"What's wrong" is something Wung's mom passed onto him.
"무슨 일이야"는 Wung의 엄마가 그에게 전달한 것입니다.
His mom?
그의 엄마?
That's right. When Wung's mom said "what's wrong" softly,
좋아요. Wung의 엄마가 "무슨 일이야"라고 부드럽게 말하자
Wung's sharp dad
Wung의 날카로운 아빠
used to melt like snow.
눈처럼 녹곤 했어요.
"What's wrong" isn't a useless technique.
"무슨 일이야"는 쓸모없는 기술이 아닙니다.
It's the greatest one ever.
그것은 역대 최고의 것입니다.
When someday Wung finds himself in a critical situation,
언젠가 Wung이 위급한 상황에 처하게 되면
that would be the day
그날이 되겠지
you can go down the mountain.
산을 내려갈 수 있습니다.
Please do it as quickly as possible.
최대한 빨리 해주세요.
Yes, don't worry.
네, 걱정하지 마세요.
- I'll contact you. - Thank you.
- 연락할게요. - 감사합니다.
I put my apartment up for sale.
나는 내 아파트를 매물로 내놓았습니다.
You're going to sell your place to get funds?
자금을 마련하기 위해 집을 팔 예정이신가요?
What are you going to do?
당신은 무엇을 할 예정입니까?
There's no other way.
다른 방법은 없습니다.
I don't even have money to pay the monthly rent for the office starting from the new year.
새해부터 사무실 월세를 낼 돈도 없어요.
Still, selling your house...
그래도 집을 파는 중...
I was going to tell you to try to contact Sae Yi.
세이에게 연락을 해보라고 하려고 했는데요.
Why would I?
내가 왜 그럴까요?
Sae Yi's company said they were interested in our game.
세이의 회사에서 우리 게임에 관심이 있다고 하더군요.
So if it doesn't work out, you should consider selling it to th—
그러니까 만약 잘 안되면, 그걸 다른 사람에게 파는 걸 고려해 봐야 해—
According to whom? I'm never selling it.
누구에 따르면? 나는 그것을 결코 팔지 않습니다.
Since you don't have money.
돈이 없으니까.
I told you I selling my house. You don't have to worry about it.
내가 집을 팔겠다고 말했잖아. 걱정할 필요가 없습니다.
I didn't know this would be this hard.
이게 이렇게 어려울 줄은 몰랐어요.
It's really not easy to start up a company.
회사를 창업하는 것은 정말 쉽지 않습니다.
Why aren't things going the way we want?
왜 일이 우리가 원하는 대로 진행되지 않는 걸까요?
Honestly, I don't have any money to contribute so I can't really say much,
솔직히 기부할 돈이 없어서 별로 말씀드릴 수가 없네요,
but don't you miss those days
하지만 그 시절을 놓치지 마세요
when we used to get paid monthly and ate warm meals?
월급도 받고 따뜻한 밥도 먹던 시절?
This is the last box. Please check that there isn't anything left.
이것이 마지막 상자입니다. 남은 것이 없는지 확인해주세요.
All right, thank you.
알겠습니다. 감사합니다.
♫ I looked forward to your heart ♫
♫ 당신의 마음을 기대했어요 ♫
That's fabric softener!
섬유유연제에요!
♫ It finally returned. ♫
♫ 드디어 돌아왔네요. ♫
♫ I want to be comforted ♫
♫ 위로받고 싶어 ♫
SLW Studio
SLW 스튜디오
♫ I was looking forward to your heart ♫
♫ 네 마음을 기대하고 있었어 ♫
♫ It finally returned. ♫
♫ 드디어 돌아왔네요. ♫
♫ I want hang onto you ♫
♫ 난 당신을 붙잡고 싶어요 ♫
♫ Before we get farther apart ♫
♫ 우리가 더 멀어지기 전에 ♫
Did you make it home safely?
집에 무사히 잘 도착하셨나요?
Yes, where are you?
응, 어디야?
I'm at home.
나는 집에있다.
Did you eat?
식사하셨나요?
Yes, a little.
네, 조금요.
Hey, Yumi.
안녕, 유미.
Were you sleeping?
자고 있었나요?
No, I'm not sleeping yet.
아니요, 아직 자지 않았습니다.
Where are you right now?
지금 어디 계시나요?
I'm home.
나는 집에있다.
Wung, I'm in front of your house right now.
웅, 나 지금 네 집 앞에 있어.
What?
무엇?
You're not home, are you?
집에 없지, 그렇지?
Where are you?
어디세요?
Wung, what's going on?
웅, 무슨 일이야?
Yumi.
유미.
You sold your apartment?
아파트를 팔았나요?
Yes.
예.
When?
언제?
About a month ago.
약 한 달 전.
Did you sell your house to develop your company?
회사를 발전시키기 위해 집을 팔았습니까?
I ran out of funds.
자금이 부족했습니다.
I had no other choice.
나에게는 다른 선택의 여지가 없었다.
And you didn't tell me that something this big was going on?
그런데 이렇게 큰 일이 벌어지고 있다는 걸 나한테 말하지 않았나요?
It's not a big deal. It's something everybody encounters when starting up a company.
그것은 큰 문제가 아니다. 회사를 창업하면 누구나 겪는 일이죠.
How can this be not a big deal,
이게 어떻게 별일이 아닐 수 있지,
when you're living without a home like this?
이런 집도 없이 살아요?
Look at yourself. With your beard and your sleeping bag.
너 자신을 봐. 수염과 침낭으로.
What the hell is this...
이게 대체 무슨 일이야...
I'm growing my beard longer on purpose, so it doesn't count.
일부러 수염을 길게 기르고 있으니 그건 의미가 없습니다.
You're joking at a time like this?
이런 시기에 농담하는 겁니까?
I'm asking if you are joking at a time like this?
이런 시기에 농담하는 거냐고 묻고 싶습니다.
Am I really your girlfriend?
내가 정말 네 여자친구야?
Why do you always keep secrets from me whenever something important happens?
왜 중요한 일이 있을 때마다 나한테는 항상 비밀을 지켜주나요?
Master!
주인!
Master, something serious is going on in the village right now.
선생님, 지금 마을에는 심각한 일이 벌어지고 있습니다.
Something big must have happened.
뭔가 큰 일이 일어난 게 틀림없어요.
The time has come for you to go down the mountain.
이제 산을 내려갈 시간이 왔습니다.
Go stop what is about to happen to Wung and come back.
가서 Wung에게 일어날 일을 멈추고 돌아오세요.
Pardon? Are you talking about me?
뭐라고요? 나에 대해 말하는거야?
How?
어떻게?
It's cold.
춥다.
Use "what's wrong?".
"무슨 일이야?"를 사용하세요.
What?!
무엇?!
'What's wrong?' isn't a technique to calm or appease people.
'무슨 일이야?' 사람을 진정시키거나 달래는 기술이 아닙니다.
It's a technique telling that our relationship is very precious.
우리의 관계가 매우 소중하다는 것을 알려주는 기술입니다.
So the true 'what's wrong' technique,
그렇다면 진정한 '무엇이 잘못되었는가' 기술은
should contain fear.
두려움을 담고 있어야 합니다.
The fear that she could leave him.
그녀가 그를 떠날 수도 있다는 두려움.
Send that feeling to her.
그 느낌을 그녀에게 보내세요.
Seriously but not bluntly.
진지하지만 무뚝뚝하지는 않습니다.
Softly but not lightly.
부드럽지만 가볍지는 않습니다.
With the fear that
With the fear that
this precious relationship might break.
소중한 인연이 깨질 수도 있어요.
What's wrong?
무슨 일이야?
Yumi, what's wrong?
유미, 무슨 일이야?
Seriously...
진심으로...
What's wrong? Huh?
무슨 일이야? 뭐?
I stopped it. I stopped it!
나는 그것을 멈췄다. 나는 그것을 멈췄다!
Master! "What's wrong?" worked!
주인! "무슨 일이야?" 일했다!
I stopped it!
나는 그것을 멈췄다!
Gu Wung, seriously you...
Gu Wung, 진심으로 당신은...
What should I do with you?
내가 당신을 어떻게 해야 합니까?
What the hell is all this?
이게 다 뭐야?
This place isn't too bad. I can save commuting time.
이 곳도 나쁘지 않아요. 출퇴근 시간을 절약할 수 있어요.
So this is why you told me that
그래서 당신이 나에게 그런 말을 한 이유는
I shouldn't jump into new things so carelessly.
너무 함부로 새로운 일에 뛰어들면 안 된다.
Starting new work is good, but it's something you've never done before.
새로운 일을 시작하는 것은 좋지만, 한 번도 해본 적이 없는 일입니다.
I think it's better to keep improving on what you're good at now.
지금 자신이 잘하는 것을 계속해서 발전시키는 것이 더 좋다고 생각해요.
Life doesn't go the way you want.
인생은 원하는 대로 흘러가지 않습니다.
I think we should always prepare for the worst.
우리는 항상 최악의 상황에 대비해야 한다고 생각합니다.
It's not easy.
쉽지 않습니다.
I'm telling you from experience.
경험에서 말씀드립니다.
I left a stable, well-paying company.
나는 안정적이고 보수가 좋은 회사를 떠났습니다.
But a lot of things happened, that I hadn't foreseen when I left .
하지만 떠날 때 예상하지 못했던 일들이 많이 일어났습니다.
So, since you regret doing it, you think I'll regret transferring, too?
그럼 네가 후회하니까 나도 이적을 후회할 것 같아?
I don't regret it because I will succeed in the end.
나는 결국 성공할 것이기 때문에 후회하지 않는다.
But there are too many obstacles.
하지만 장애물이 너무 많습니다.
So I meant that it'd be hard to endure unless you are really determined.
그래서 진심으로 결심하지 않으면 견디기 힘들다는 뜻이었습니다.
I like what I do, so I can endure it, but you're not sure
내가 하는 일이 좋아서 견딜 수 있는데 잘 모르겠지
if you really like marketing.
마케팅을 정말 좋아한다면.
That's what I meant.
그게 내가 의미하는 바입니다.
Think about if it's something that you like so much that you won't regret it
너무 좋아해서 후회하지 않을지 생각해 보세요
even if something were to happen.
무슨 일이 일어나더라도.
Okay.
좋아요.
I got it, so let's go to my place for now.
알았으니 일단 내 집으로 가자.
You can't live here like this.
여기서 이렇게 살 수는 없습니다.
I don't want to.
나는 원하지 않는다.
Why not?
왜 안 돼?
I don't like the idea of moving in with my girlfriend because I have nowhere to go.
갈 곳이 없어서 여자친구와 함께 이사한다는 생각이 마음에 들지 않습니다.
It's a fact that you have nowhere to go.
갈 곳이 없다는 사실입니다.
I didn't go broke or fail, I just chose to be uncomfortable for a little bit for the sake of my dream.
나는 망하거나 실패한 것이 아니라 꿈을 위해 잠시 불편함을 선택한 것뿐이다.
It's a choice I made.
그건 내가 한 선택이에요.
Please understand.
이해해주세요.
Gu Wung, you seriously ...
Gu Wung, 당신 정말...
- He's proud, even though he has no other plan. - Still, he has a sense of responsibility.
- 다른 계획은 없는데도 자랑스러워요. - 그래도 책임감은 있어요.
Let's just go. We have to think about his pride too.
그냥 가자. 우리는 그의 자존심에 대해서도 생각해야 합니다.
Does pride feed you? Provide shelter?
자존심이 당신을 먹여 살리나요? 피난처를 제공합니까?
How can we just leave after seeing this?
이걸 보고 어떻게 그냥 떠날 수가 있지?
Wung is right. We can't just move in together without thinking about it.
웅 말이 맞아요. 우리는 그것에 대해 생각하지 않고 함께 들어갈 수 없습니다.
We don't know what obstacles we'll face when we live together.
우리는 함께 살 때 어떤 장애물에 직면하게 될지 모릅니다.
And we might regret it later. But at that point we won't be able to tell him to leave.
그리고 나중에 후회할 수도 있습니다. 하지만 그 시점에서 우리는 그에게 떠나라고 말할 수 없습니다.
He said you won't regret it if it's something that you like.
좋아하는 일이라면 후회하지 않을 거라고 하더군요.
Don't we like Wung?
우리는 Wung을 좋아하지 않나요?
Then why are you worrying in advance that we might regret it?
그럼 왜 우리가 후회할까 미리 걱정하는 겁니까?
You're good with your words.
당신은 말을 잘해요.
Let's go.
갑시다.
I'm not going, Yumi.
난 안 갈 거야, 유미.
You're really not coming?
정말 안 올 거예요?
I'll just stay here until I find a place. It's really comfortable here.
난 그냥 자리를 찾을 때까지 여기 있을게요. 여기는 정말 편해요.
- Yeah? - Yeah.
- 응? - 응.
Even if you won't see me again?
다시는 나를 볼 수 없더라도?
- What? - Even if this moment is our last moment together?
- 무엇? - 지금 이 순간이 우리가 함께하는 마지막 순간이라도?
What the heck? Are you threatening me?
도대체 뭐야? 나를 협박하는 겁니까?
Even if it's not a threat and I really mean it?
위협이 아니고 진심으로 하는 말인데도요?
- Yumi, what's wrong? - Stop that now.
- 유미 씨, 무슨 일이에요? - 이제 그만하세요.
"What's wrong" isn't working anymore.
"무슨 문제가 있나요?"가 더 이상 작동하지 않습니다.
Maybe it doesn't work twice in a row? What should I do?
어쩌면 두 번 연속으로 작동하지 않습니까? 어떻게 해야 하나요?
I will be back, Master.
또 올게요, 선생님.
- Hold on. Let me teach you another killer move. - What?
- 기다리다. 또 다른 킬러 동작을 가르쳐 드리겠습니다. - 무엇?
Wung's mom's killer move is 'what's wrong'.
웅 엄마의 킬러 행보는 '무슨 일이냐'다.
And this is Wung's dad's killer move.
그리고 이것이 Wung의 아버지의 살인적인 행동입니다.
If there is a crisis where 'what's wrong' doesn't work,
'무슨 일이냐'가 통하지 않는 위기가 닥치면
then say your name at the last moment.
그런 다음 마지막 순간에 이름을 말하세요.
I'm not just saying this.
나는 단지 이것을 말하는 것이 아닙니다.
Pack up now.
지금 짐을 꾸리세요.
Wung (Okay).
웅(알았어).
You're coming with me?
나와 함께 갈 건가요?
Wung (Yes).
웅(예).
Obedience is the only way to survive.
순종만이 살아남는 유일한 길이다.
Let's shave your beard first thing when we get home.
집에 오면 제일 먼저 수염을 깎자.
Wung (Okay).
웅(알았어).
Let's go.
갑시다.
But I'm really growing my beard—
그런데 정말 수염을 기르고 있어요—
Wung (Okay).
웅(알았어).
With the superior genes of the Gu family, Wung safely averted the crisis.
구씨 가문의 우월한 유전자로 웅은 무사히 위기를 모면했다.
But there is still a long way to go.
하지만 아직 갈 길이 멀다.
Wung's hardships will continue on in the future,
웅의 고난은 앞으로도 계속될 것이다
and my training won't stop either.
그리고 나의 훈련도 멈추지 않을 것이다.
Wake up!
깨우다!
Shoot! I'm late!
사격! 나는 늦었다!
You should've woken me if you were up already.
이미 일어났으면 나를 깨웠어야 했는데.
I did wake you but you said you can sleep more.
내가 깨웠는데 더 자도 된다고 하셨어요.
That was sleep talking!
그건 잠꼬대였어!
What do you want for breakfast?
아침 식사로 무엇을 원하세요?
I don't know! I'm not eating.
모르겠습니다! 나는 먹지 않는다.
Yumi, eat this before you go.
유미 씨, 가기 전에 이것 좀 먹어요.
No, I'm late.
아니요, 늦었어요.
You're not late yet. I'll get a cab and drop you off on my way. It'll only take 20 minutes.
아직 늦지 않았습니다. 내가 택시를 타고 가는 길에 당신을 내려줄게요. 20분밖에 안 걸릴 거예요.
You're broke. What cab?
당신은 파산했습니다. 무슨 택시?
What do you mean? I'm rich in cash because I sold my place.
무슨 뜻이에요? 나는 집을 팔아서 현금이 부자가 되었습니다.
- I can ride the cab hundreds of times. - Aigoo.
- 택시를 수백 번 탈 수 있어요. - 아이고.
Sit.
앉다.
But Wung, I'm going to transfer to the marketing department.
그런데 Wung, 나는 마케팅 부서로 옮길 예정이에요.
I made up my mind.
나는 결심했다.
Did you give it a lot of thought?
많이 생각해 보셨나요?
Not a lot but I want to try it.
많지는 않지만 꼭 해보고 싶습니다.
I'm not responsible if you regret it.
후회하시면 책임지지 않습니다.
Well, just because you have a clear goal, it doesn't mean you will be successful.
글쎄요, 목표가 분명하다고 해서 성공할 수 있는 것은 아닙니다.
I don't know, but after trying it, I might like it,
잘 모르겠지만, 사용해 보고 나면 마음에 들 수도 있겠네요,
and I might have a new goal while trying it.
그리고 그것을 시도하다 보면 새로운 목표가 생길 수도 있다.
Don't you think?
그렇게 생각하지 않나요?
You're right. Eat.
당신 말이 맞아요. 먹다.
Actually, many important things in life often start unexpectedly.
실제로 인생에서 많은 중요한 일들은 예기치 않게 시작되는 경우가 많습니다.
Just like us now.
지금 우리처럼요.
♫ Nightfallin'  ♫
♫ 나이트폴링 ♫
♫ at the end of the sun setting ♫
♫ 해가 지는 마지막 순간에 ♫
It's not like I'm starting a business like you did. I'm just transferring departments.
나는 당신처럼 사업을 시작하지 않습니다. 부서를 옮기는 중이에요.
They won't kick me out.
그들은 나를 쫓아내지 않을 것이다.
You never know. You might be the first one to make the record of being kicked out.
당신은 결코 알지 못합니다. 쫓겨난 기록을 세운 사람은 당신이 처음일지도 모릅니다.
Watch it.
조심하세요.
There's a taxi. Let's run.
택시가 있어요. 달리자.
♫ I feel you intensifying ♫
♫ 당신이 점점 더 격렬해지는 걸 느껴요 ♫
♫ Nightfalling ♫
♫ 해질녘 ♫
Hello.
안녕하세요.
♫ I'm hiding the especially red cheeks ♫
♫ 유난히 붉은 볼을 숨기고 있어요 ♫
♫ Yes I know ♫
♫ 네, 알아요 ♫
What time will you be done today?
오늘은 몇시에 끝나나요?
Probably around 8?
아마 8시쯤?
Then let's have dinner together. I'll have it ready.
그럼 같이 저녁 먹자. 제가 준비하겠습니다.
Fine. Have a good day.
괜찮은. 좋은 하루 보내세요.
- See you at home. - Yes.
- 집에서 봐요. - 예.
♫ When this night passes ♫
♫ 이 밤이 지나면 ♫
♫ Oh we'll know ♫
♫ 아, 우리가 알게 될 거야 ♫
Sometimes things you started without thinking can give you greater happiness.
때로는 아무 생각 없이 시작한 일이 더 큰 행복을 줄 수도 있습니다.
♫ You and I ♫
♫ 당신과 나 ♫
Hello.
안녕하세요.
Oh, good morning.
아, 좋은 아침이에요.
Oh, right. I have something to tell you.
아, 그렇죠. 당신에게 할 말이 있습니다.
What is it?
그것은 무엇입니까?
I'll go to the marketing department.
나는 마케팅 부서로 갈 것이다.
Although I'm a little scared.
조금 겁이 나지만.
You made a good decision.
좋은 결정을 내리셨습니다.
It is, right?
그렇죠?
Of course. I'm really glad.
물론. 정말 기쁘네요.
Sorry?
죄송합니다?
I'm sure there will be obstacles but I don't want to know them in advance.
분명 장애물이 있을 텐데 미리 알고 싶지는 않아요.
Aren't you getting in?
안 들어가나요?
Episode 31: Gu Wung's World
31회: 구웅의 세계
♫ Because today on my day  ♫
♫ 오늘은 내 하루니까 ♫
♫ he softly approaches again ♫
♫ 그는 다시 부드럽게 다가온다 ♫
♫ I didn't even expect it ♫
♫ 기대도 안 했는데 ♫
♫ he is playing a joke. ♫
♫ 그는 농담을 하고 있어요. ♫
♫ Why of all days this morning, ♫
♫ 왜 오늘 아침엔, ♫
♫ without any preparation ♫
♫ 아무 준비도 없이 ♫
♫ did you leave my room? ♫
♫ 내 방에서 나갔나요? ♫
Things I've learned while living with Wung:
Wung과 함께 살면서 배운 것들:
Wung doesn't sleep in.
Wung은 늦잠을 자지 않아요.
Wake up! ♫ it's not about something I can understand ♫
깨우다! ♫ 그건 내가 이해할 수 있는 문제가 아니야 ♫
♫ To me who am spending an unexpected day ♫
♫ 뜻밖의 하루를 보내고 있는 나에게 ♫
♫ Sing a song, song song song song ♫
♫ 노래를 불러요, 노래 노래 노래 노래 ♫
Kim Yumi, wake up!
김유미, 일어나라!
No.. I'm going to sleep for ten more minutes.
아니요.. 10분만 더 자겠습니다.
- I don't fall for that anymore. - I'm serious. ♫ so that I can feel your love love love love ♫
- 난 더 이상 그런 말에 속지 않아요. - 진심이에요. ♫ 너의 사랑을 느낄 수 있게 사랑 사랑 사랑 ♫
♫ Can’t think the word that I wanna say ♫
♫ 내가 말하고 싶은 단어가 생각나지 않네요 ♫
♫ To me who is about to cry ♫
♫ 울기 직전인 나에게 ♫
It's cold...
추워요...
♫ sing a song song song song ♫
♫ 노래를 불러요 노래 노래 노래 ♫
Do I have to resort to this to wake you up? I'm going in.
당신을 깨우려면 이 방법을 써야 하나요? 들어갈 거야.
♫ so that I can feel your love love love love ♫
♫ 너의 사랑을 느낄 수 있게 사랑 사랑 사랑 ♫
♫ In a corner of my heart ♫
♫ 내 마음 한구석에 ♫
What are you doing?
뭐하세요?
You're not getting up.
당신은 일어나지 않습니다.
You're not getting up, you're not getting up!
너 안 일어나, 안 일어나!
I'm up!
나는 일어났다!
Mission clear.
미션 클리어.
Thanks to him, I don't have to worry about being late.
그 사람 덕분에 나는 늦는 것에 대해 걱정할 필요가 없습니다.
Why don't you eat this first before washing up?
설거지하기 전에 이거 먼저 먹어보는 게 어때?
Wow! It's toast.
우와! 토스트예요.
- You know how to make toast? - This is all I know how to make.
- 토스트 만드는 법을 아시나요? - 제가 만드는 방법은 이게 전부예요.
Fried eggs and toast
달걀 프라이와 토스트
Thank you for the food.
음식을 주셔서 감사합니다.
♫ It's not about something I can understand ♫
♫ 내가 이해할 수 있는 문제는 아니야 ♫
It's good.
좋다.
- Really? - It's really good.
- 정말? - 정말 좋아요.
♫ Sing a song, song song song song ♫
♫ 노래를 불러요, 노래 노래 노래 노래 ♫
The toast that Wung makes is the best.
웅이 해주는 토스트가 제일 맛있어요.
♫ so that I can feel your love love love love ♫
♫ 너의 사랑을 느낄 수 있게 사랑 사랑 사랑 ♫
Wung, I bought some churros! Let's eat churros with coffee.
웅, 나 츄러스 샀어! 츄러스를 커피와 함께 먹자.
And, Wung likes organizing.
그리고 Wung은 정리하는 것을 좋아합니다.
Wung, did you organize the cups?
웅, 컵 정리는 잘 했어?
Huh?
뭐?
- Yes. The sizes were so different. - I see.
- 예. 사이즈가 너무 다양했어요. - 알겠어요.
I left the rest in the cupboard.
나머지는 찬장에 놔뒀어요.
Is that all right? They weren't really used anyway.
괜찮습니까? 어쨌든 그들은 실제로 사용되지 않았습니다.
I like it. I bought some churros, let's eat.
좋아요. 츄러스 사왔으니 먹자.
Okay.
좋아요.
What are you doing? Are you looking for a certain book?
뭐하세요? 특정 책을 찾고 계십니까?
No, its not that.
아니요, 그게 아닙니다.
How are you categorizing these books?
이 책들을 어떻게 분류하고 있나요?
Categorize? I just put them in.
분류? 그냥 넣었어요.
You don't have a system?
시스템이 없나요?
It looks like all of the books here are romance novels.
여기 있는 책은 다 로맨스 소설인 것 같아요.
Yes. I really love romance novels.
예. 저는 로맨스 소설을 정말 좋아해요.
You have romance and not romance.
당신에게는 로맨스가 있지만 로맨스는 없습니다.
I think it will be much better to separate romance by author and then organize it alphabetically.
로맨스 소설은 작가별로 구분해서 알파벳순으로 정리하는 게 훨씬 나을 것 같아요.
- Huh? - Then it'll be much easier to find books.
- 뭐? - 그러면 책을 찾는 것이 훨씬 더 쉬울 거예요.
It would be easier. But when would I have time to do that?
더 쉬울 것입니다. 그런데 언제 그런 일을 할 시간이 있을까요?
Or do you want to do it for me?
아니면 나를 위해 그것을 하시겠습니까?
- Really? Can I? - What?
- 정말? 할 수 있나요? - 무엇?
Should I organize them? I'm really good at things like this.
정리해야 할까요? 저는 이런 일을 정말 잘해요.
Sure, you can do it. That'd be good for me.
물론입니다. 할 수 있습니다. 그게 나한테는 좋을 것 같아.
Thank you! I'll organize really well!
감사합니다! 정말 잘 정리하겠습니다!
You don't really need to thank me..
나한테 고마워할 필요는 없어..
Since there are six shelves,
선반이 6개이므로
if we distribute three consonants for each shelf, then it'll be just right.
각 선반에 세 개의 자음을 배치하면 딱 맞을 것입니다.
ABC, DEF, GHI, JKL... YZ! (The Korean alphabet has 14 consonants and no name begins with a vowel)
ABC, DEF, GHI, JKL... YZ! (한국어의 자음은 14개이며 모음으로 시작하는 이름은 없습니다.)
And then the rest...
그리고 나머지는...
What's with him? Why does he like it so much?
그 사람은 뭐야? 그 사람은 왜 그렇게 좋아하는 걸까요?
Does Wung like house chores?
Wung은 집안일을 좋아하나요?
Oh, so that's why his house was always so clean.
아, 그래서 그 사람 집은 항상 깨끗했거든요.
No wonder.
당연합니다.
What are Wung's cells like? I bet its so different from our Housework cell.
Wung의 세포는 어떤가요? 우리 집안일 세포와는 너무 다를 것 같아요.
Are you guys talking about me?
지금 내 얘기를 하고 있는 거야?
Yes, you! I want to see how different his cell is compared to you!
응, 너! 그 사람의 세포가 당신과 얼마나 다른지 보고 싶어요!
All right!
괜찮은!
Even when Wung came over the first day,
Wung이 첫날에 왔을 때도
Thank you.
감사합니다.
Let's go.
갑시다.
I turned off the heater before leaving, so it'll be cold.
떠나기 전에 히터를 꺼서 추울 것 같아요.
- Wait Reason ... did we clean? - Clean?
- 잠깐만요 이유는... 청소는 했나요? - 깨끗한?
This is the first time bringing Wung in without us preparing.
우리가 준비하지 않고 Wung을 데려온 것은 이번이 처음입니다.
We probably cleaned, right? Because I'm worried.
아마 청소를 했겠죠? 걱정이 되니까.
When we left in the morning I think everything was–
아침에 떠났을 때 모든 게 다-
That! The laundry on the drying rack!
저것! 건조대에 빨래를!
You didn't take in the laundry? What were you even doing on your day off?
세탁물을 맡기지 않았나요? 쉬는 날에도 뭐 하고 있었나요?
Sit, sit.
앉아, 앉아.
Reason, we're in trouble. That is not all!
이유야, 우리가 곤경에 빠졌어. 그게 다가 아니다!
Is there something else?
다른 것이 있나요?
Oh no! Where did Housecleaner go?!
안 돼! 하우스클리너는 어디로 갔나요?!
Agh! What were you doing not folding the laundry?
아! 빨래 안접고 뭐하고 있었나요?
I was going to do it tomorrow. I guess I'll do it now!
내일 하려고 했는데 이제 할 것 같아요!
You're going to fold the laundry while Wung is here?!
웡이 여기 있는 동안 빨래를 개실 건가요?!
Then I guess I'll do it tomorrow!
그럼 내일 할 것 같아요!
You need to hurry and figure it out, Wung is already here!
서둘러 알아내야 합니다. Wung은 이미 여기에 있습니다!
Really? Then I guess I just need to do a little laundry kick!
정말? 그렇다면 빨래를 좀 하면 될 것 같아요!
Let's go ... laundry kick!
가자... 빨래킥!
Finishing it off well! Laundry kick: Technology to send laundry to the 4th dimension
잘 마무리하세요! 세탁킥 : 세탁물을 4차원으로 보내는 기술
Are you satisfied?
만족하시나요?
That's...still not everything.
그게...아직 전부는 아닙니다.
Look at the pillows ... the drool marks.
베개를 보세요. 침 자국을 보세요.
What are we going to do about the hair?!
머리카락은 어떻게 할 건가요?!
I told you to wash the pillowcases more often!
내가 베갯잇 좀 더 자주 세탁하라고 했잖아!
You did, you did. I was going to do it next week.
그랬어요, 그랬어요. 다음주에 하려고 했는데
- Why I ought to...! - It's all right!
- 내가 왜 그래야만 하는가...! - 괜찮아요!
I know a method that makes them look good as new.
나는 그것들을 새 것처럼 보이게 만드는 방법을 알고 있습니다.
You just got to turn the pillows 180 degrees.
베개를 180도 돌려주면 됩니다.
Now they look clean, right?
이제 깨끗해 보이죠?
It's not something to be proud of.
자랑스러워할 일이 아닙니다.
And, that!
그리고, 그거!
The snack you were munching on yesterday. Why didn't you clean it?
어제 먹던 간식. 왜 청소하지 않았나요?
♫ Even if I walk carefully ♫
♫ 조심스럽게 걸어도 ♫
♫ My heart is far away there ♫
♫ 내 마음은 저기 멀리 있어요 ♫
♫ Even at night when everyone else is asleep ♫
♫ 모두가 잠든 밤에도 ♫
♫ It's racing wide awake ♫
♫ 잠에서 깨어나 질주하고 있어요 ♫
That's not a problem. The answer is there!
그건 문제가 되지 않습니다. 답은 거기에 있습니다!
You just got to hide it as one of the books.
그냥 책 중 하나로 숨겨두면 됩니다.
Doesn't that look natural?
그게 자연스러워 보이지 않나요?
Oh my goodness.
아, 맙소사.
Now it's time for me to sleep! Goodnight!
이제 잠을 잘 시간이에요! 안녕히 주무세요!
♫ Even if I spend a day when nothing happens ♫
♫ 아무 일도 일어나지 않는 하루를 보내도 ♫
We've always lived like this.
우리는 늘 이렇게 살아왔습니다.
But.. look at Wung. Look how different he is.
그런데.. 웡을 보세요. 그가 얼마나 다른지보세요.
Wung, coffee.
웅, 커피.
♫ Even if I knew I can't do anything with my heart ♫
♫ 마음으로는 아무것도 할 수 없다는 걸 알면서도 ♫
Wung, should I help you?
웅, 내가 도와줄까?
There are too many Lees. There are too many Lees.
리스가 너무 많아요. 리스가 너무 많아요.
- Huh? -You have a lot of books by the author Lee Dong Gun.
- 뭐? -이동건 작가의 책이 많아요.
Yes, I like the author Lee Dong Gun.
네, 저는 이동건 작가를 좋아해요.
And that is why there isn't enough space for the third consonant. There are too many Lee's.
그래서 세 번째 자음을 넣을 공간이 부족합니다. 이이 너무 많아요.
Ah ... what should I do?
아... 어떻게 해야 하지?
Wung, it doesn't matter to me if the books are in alphabetical order.
웅, 책이 알파벳순으로 되어 있는지는 나에게 중요하지 않아요.
Oh?
오?
This isn't a book.
이것은 책이 아닙니다.
These are crackers! Why is this here?
크래커들이에요! 이게 왜 여기 있지?
Oh wow. You're right. How did this ... get there?
아 와. 당신 말이 맞아요. 이게 어떻게... 거기까지 갔지?
That's it! Now if I put these last books in there ...
그게 다야! 이제 이 마지막 책들을 거기에 넣으면...
It's done! Book shelf, success! Success!
끝났어요! 책꽂이, 성공! 성공!
- Are you finished? - Yes.
- 끝났어요? - 예.
Good job. Now come and eat this! It's all cooled now, so it won't be as good.
잘했어요. 이제 와서 이거 먹어! 지금은 다 식어서 별로 좋지 않을 거예요.
There's a lot of dust on the floor, so I think I'll clean it first.
바닥에 먼지가 너무 많아서 먼저 청소를 해야 할 것 같아요.
I'll clean it. You come eat.
내가 청소할게. 너는 와서 먹어라.
No, no. Where is the mop?
아니, 아니. 대걸레는 어디에 있나요?
The length of this ... 40 cm.
이것의 길이는 ... 40cm입니다.
And the floor is...
바닥은...
from the bookshelf to the bed, 160 cm.
책장에서 침대까지 160cm.
Can I wipe it all perfectly, in just 4 sweeps?
단 4번의 청소만으로 완벽하게 지울 수 있을까요?
Let's do it.
해보자.
Look at this! It fits perfectly.
이것 좀 보세요! 완벽하게 맞습니다.
Look at it. This is it!
보세요. 이것이다!
It's so thrilling.
너무 짜릿해요.
Thrilled ... while cleaning?
설렘... 청소하다가?
It's my first time seeing someone get so excited by cleaning.
누군가가 청소를 하면서 그렇게 흥분하는 모습은 처음 봤습니다.
On top of that, that person being my boyfriend,
게다가 그 사람은 내 남자친구야
is even more surprising.
더욱 놀랍습니다.
Before we lived together, I didn't know...
같이 살기 전에는 몰랐는데...
What?
무엇?
What is it? What are you looking at?
그것은 무엇입니까? 무엇을 보고 있나요?
Yumi.
유미.
- Yes? - Can you get up for a sec?
- 예? - 잠시 일어나 주시겠어요?
The poster is too far to the left in relation to the bed.
포스터가 침대에 비해 너무 왼쪽에 있습니다.
- What? - It's too late to put in a new nail.
- 무엇? - 새 손톱을 넣기에는 너무 늦었습니다.
I have to push the bed.
침대를 밀어야 해요.
So as to line up the poster with the middle of the bed. Okay.
포스터를 침대 중앙에 정렬하도록. 좋아요.
Is this good? Yumi, take a look.
이게 좋은가요? 유미 씨, 이것 좀 보세요.
- Is this good? - Hmm? Yes ...
- 이거 좋은가요? - 흠? 네...
I think it's good.
나는 그것이 좋다고 생각한다.
Is it?
그렇습니까?
Okay, it's good.
좋아요, 좋습니다.
Now I feel better.
이제 기분이 좋아졌습니다.
- Yumi, what do you think? - Huh? I like it.
- 유미 씨는 어떻게 생각해요? - 뭐? 좋아요.
Wung loves to keep things organized.
Wung은 물건을 정리하는 것을 좋아합니다.
Perfect.
완벽한.
This is impressive.
이것은 인상적이다.
You hung the pots by their size.
크기에 맞춰 화분을 걸어두셨어요.
I couldn't just let it go.
그냥 놔둘 수가 없었어요.
Your nickname from now on is neat freak. It's confirmed.
이제부터 네 별명은 깔끔한 괴물이다. 확인되었습니다.
At this rate, you're going to organize my underwear drawer.
이대로라면 내 속옷 서랍을 정리하게 될 텐데.
Why aren't you answering? Did you already do it?
왜 대답하지 않습니까? 이미 했나요?
- I didn't yet. - Not "yet". Don't do it!
- 아직은 안 그랬어요. - 아직 아님". 하지 마세요!
But I can do it really well.
하지만 나는 정말 잘할 수 있어요.
- No. Don't do it. No way. - I got it.
- 아뇨. 그러지 마세요. 안 돼요. - 알겠어요.
I won't do it. Okay. Sit.
나는 그것을하지 않을 것입니다. 좋아요. 앉다.
- You won't do it, right? - Right.
- 안 할 거예요, 그렇죠? - 오른쪽.
Enjoy your food.
음식을 즐기세요.
Gosh.
이런.
You're a lot cleaner than I thought.
생각보다 훨씬 깨끗하시네요.
I didn't know you like organizing this much.
당신이 이렇게 정리하는 걸 좋아하는 줄은 몰랐어요.
It's not that I like organizing.
내가 정리하는 걸 좋아하는 건 아니다.
I like finding the continuous regularity of an arrangement.
나는 배열의 지속적인 규칙성을 찾는 것을 좋아합니다.
Cleaning is a kind of a mathematical process.
청소는 일종의 수학적 과정입니다.
If you make a clear algorithm for cleaning, you can apply it anywhere.
청소를 위한 명확한 알고리즘을 만들면 어디에나 적용할 수 있습니다.
And I'm neat because of that.
그리고 나는 그것 때문에 깔끔하다.
That's so impressive. He's diligent and efficient.
정말 인상적이네요. 그는 부지런하고 효율적입니다.
He even has scientific reasoning. He's at a master's level.
그는 심지어 과학적인 추론도 가지고 있습니다. 그는 마스터 수준입니다.
Hey, don't you feel anything?
야, 아무 느낌 없어?
I do. Wung's great!
그래요. 웅 대단해요!
Not that. Don't you think you should learn from him?
그렇지 않습니다. 그 사람에게서 배워야 한다고 생각하지 않나요?
What do I need to learn?
무엇을 배워야 합니까?
The person who loves doing it should just do it. I'm off to get some rest.
좋아하는 사람은 그냥 하면 된다. 나는 좀 쉬러 가겠어.
Should I kill her?
내가 그녀를 죽여야 할까?
Wung's housework cell?
웅의 집안일 감방?
Yes. Since you've been to Wung's village, you've probably seen him.
예. 당신은 Wung의 마을에 가본 적이 있기 때문에 아마도 그를 본 적이 있을 것입니다.
I want to learn their technique and pass it down to our housework cell.
그들의 기술을 배워서 우리 집안일 세포에 전해 주고 싶다.
Well... from what I can remember, Wung didn't have a housework cell.
글쎄요... 제가 기억하는 바로는 Wung에게는 집안일을 하는 감방이 없었습니다.
What? How can he be so good at housework when he doesn't have a housework cell?
무엇? 가사실도 없는데 어떻게 집안일을 그렇게 잘할 수 있겠어요?
Instead, he has a huge artificial intelligence cell.
대신 그는 거대한 인공지능 세포를 갖고 있다.
An articial intelligence cell?
인공지능 세포?
Run the algorithm now.
지금 알고리즘을 실행해 보세요.
Running the algorithm.
알고리즘을 실행합니다.
- There is such a thing? - Yes.
- 그런 게 있어요? - 예.
When there was a problem, that was what solved everything.
문제가 생겼을 때 그것이 모든 것을 해결한 것이었습니다.
Housework is probably determined there, too.
집안일도 거기서 결정되겠죠.
I'm jealous. I'm really jealous.
나는 질투한다. 정말 질투난다.
How efficient and scientific!
얼마나 효율적이고 과학적인가!
You don't even have to nag at the lazy housework cell.
게으른 집안일 감방에서 잔소리할 필요도 없습니다.
And my work would be reduced so much!
그리고 내 일이 너무 줄어들 것입니다!
That's the very world I've been dreaming of.
그것이 바로 내가 꿈꿔왔던 세상이다.
- Love, I have a favor to ask you. - A favor?
- 사랑해요, 부탁이 하나 있어요. - 부탁이요?
Love wormhole opens pretty often these days.
요즘 러브웜홀이 자주 열리는군요.
Yeah, I guess.
응, 그런 것 같아.
When the wormhole opens today...
오늘 웜홀이 열리면...
Yumi, coffee.
유미, 커피.
It's hot.
덥다.
Wung, look over there. Isn't the moon exceptionally yellow today?
웅, 저기 좀 보세요. 오늘은 달이 유난히 노란색이지 않나요?
- Is it? - Yeah, look over there.
- 그렇죠? - 응, 저기 좀 봐.
- No, look at me. - Hmm?
- 아니, 나를 봐. - 흠?
Send me to Wung's village.
나를 웅의 마을로 보내주세요.
Now!
지금!
Reason, be careful.
이유야, 조심해라.
I'm not scared, Love. I'm so excited.
난 두렵지 않아요, 사랑해요. 정말 신난다.
I'll learn a lot!
많이 배우겠습니다!
Wow, I'm finally here. So this is Wung's world.
와, 드디어 왔네요. 이것이 Wung의 세계입니다.
A world ruled by science and logic. A world where reason is the most valuable.
과학과 논리가 지배하는 세상. 이성이 가장 가치 있는 세상.
What is that?
저게 뭐에요?
No!
아니요!
No! Don't come to me!
아니요! 나에게 오지 마세요!
Right, Naughtysaurus is probably on the loose right now.
그렇죠, Naughtysaurus는 아마도 지금 당장 풀려날 것입니다.
Would Reason be all right?
이성은 괜찮을까요?
No, let me down!
아니, 나를 실망시키세요!
Yumi is so sexy!
유미는 정말 섹시해요!
I can't hold it in anymore!
더 이상 참을 수 없어요!
I want to go home!
집에 가고 싶어요!
Wung's world was a world of chaos, where scientific logic and the madness of a beast coexist.
웅의 세계는 과학적인 논리와 짐승의 광기가 공존하는 혼돈의 세계였다.
Let me down! After that, I never dreamed of that place again.
나를 실망시키세요! 그 후로 나는 다시는 그런 곳을 꿈꾸지 않았다.
Episode 32: Cake and Keyboard
에피소드 32: 케이크와 키보드
Daehan Noodles
대한국수
Assistant Manager Yumi.
유미 대리.
Oh, Assistant Manager Yu.
아, 유 대리.
Are you on your way home? I'm jealous.
집에 가는 중이신가요? 나는 질투한다.
- Are you not going home? - I'm working overtime today.
- 집에 안 갈 거야? - 오늘 야근을 해요.
- You know you're starting at marketing department starting next week, right? - Yes.
- 다음 주부터 마케팅 부서에 출근하는 거 아시죠? - 예.
If you have any questions regarding the transfer, let me know.
이전과 관련하여 궁금한 점이 있으면 알려주세요.
- Questions? - Yes, don't you have any?
- 질문? - 네, 없어요?
I do have a question.
질문이 있습니다.
The marketing department has a higher salary compared to other departments.
마케팅 부서는 다른 부서에 비해 급여가 높습니다.
So is Yumi getting that much as well?
그럼 유미씨도 그만큼 많이 받는 건가요?
- Ask this, Yumi. - What if she isn't?
- 유미 씨, 물어보세요. - 만약 그렇지 않다면요?
It not, she shouldn't go. Why bother to transfer?
그렇지 않아요, 그녀는 가지 말아야 해요. 귀찮게 왜 옮기나요?
Stingy, you said you'll be my best supporter—
인색한데, 네가 내 최고의 지지자가 될 거라고 했잖아—
Go ahead and ask Yumi. Tell him no if they aren't.
가서 유미에게 물어보세요. 그렇지 않다면 그에게 거절하십시오.
Umm, I do have a question.
음, 질문이 있어요.
- What is it? - By chance, my sal—
- 그게 뭐죠? - 우연히 내 친구가—
Sal?
남자 이름?
Never mind. It's nothing. It's nothing.
괜찮아요. 그것은 아무것도 아니다. 그것은 아무것도 아니다.
I'll ask you when I think of something.
생각나는 게 있으면 물어볼게요.
Sure. Have a great weekend.
확신하는. 즐거운 주말 보내세요.
You, too, Assistant Manager Yu.
당신도 유 대리입니다.
Why is it so hard to talk about money?
돈에 관해 이야기하는 것이 왜 그렇게 어려운가요?
- Oh, right! Assistant Manager Yumi. - Yes?
- 아, 그렇죠! 유미 대리. - 예?
Did you hear about your salary?
연봉 얘기 들었어?
What? No.
무엇? 아니요.
You'll get a raise, too. I'll let you know the exact amount some other time.
당신도 급여 인상을 받게 될 것입니다. 정확한 금액은 다시 알려드리겠습니다.
Oh, sure.
아, 물론이죠.
Goodbye.
안녕히 가세요.
Stingy
인색하다
Let's work hard, Writer.
열심히 합시다, 작가님.
Daehan Noodles
대한국수
Hello? Wung, where are you?
안녕하세요? 웅, 어디야?
I just left the office.
방금 사무실을 나왔어요.
I just left, too. Wung, let's stop by the grocery store first.
나도 방금 떠났다. 웅, 먼저 식료품점에 들르자.
We don't have any food at home. Let's make something yummy.
우리 집에는 먹을 것이 하나도 없어요. 맛있는 것을 만들어 봅시다.
Yumi.
유미.
Yumi!
유미!
Wung.
웅.
I got here really fast, so I started shopping.
여기 정말 빨리 도착해서 쇼핑을 시작했어요.
Why did you get so much stuff?
왜 그렇게 많은 물건을 얻었나요?
Wung, they said I'm getting a raise.
웅, 급여가 인상될 거라고 하더군요.
- Really? - Yeah.
- 정말? - 응.
Marketing department always has the highest salary at my company.
우리 회사에서는 마케팅 부서가 항상 연봉이 가장 높습니다.
And I guess they'll match that. I think I'll get a big raise.
그리고 나는 그들이 그것과 일치할 것이라고 생각합니다. 내 생각엔 연봉 인상이 클 것 같아.
That's good.
좋아요.
It is good.
좋습니다.
So we can splurge today.
그래서 우리는 오늘 돈을 과시할 수 있습니다.
Hey, mandu are 'one plus one.' (mandu: dumplings | 1+1= buy one, get one free)
안녕하세요, 만두는 '1 더하기 1' 입니다. (만두: 만두 | 1+1= 1개 사면 1개 무료)
Wait! That's a little...
기다리다! 그건 좀...
It's not a lot. We can freeze it.
많지는 않습니다. 우리는 그것을 얼릴 수 있습니다.
That's not what I meant.
내 말은 그런 뜻이 아니었어.
This is tastier than that.
그것보다 이게 더 맛있어요.
Yeah? But that's not one plus one.
응? 그러나 그것은 1 더하기 1이 아닙니다.
That's two 400 grams, two of them 800 grams for 8,000 won (≈$7).
400g 2개인데 800g 2개에 8,000원(약 7달러)입니다.
And this is 5,500 won (≈$5) for 500 grams.
그리고 이것은 500그램에 5,500원입니다.
That's 1,000 won per 100 grams but this is 1,100 won per 100 grams.
100g당 1,000원인데 이건 100g당 1,100원이에요.
It's only a 100 won (less than 1 cent) difference. Shouldn't we go with the taste?
고작 100원(1센트 미만) 차이입니다. 맛으로 가볼까요?
You're fast with calculation, Gu Wung.
계산이 빠르군요, Gu Wung.
I am pretty fast.
나는 꽤 빠르다.
Then, pan-fried mandus for dinner tonight?
그럼 오늘 저녁은 만두튀김?
How about pairing them with bibim-ramyeon? (Spicy instant noodle without broth)
비빔라면과 함께 먹으면 어떨까요? (육수없는 매운라면)
Your culinary sense is no joke either, Gu Wung.
구웅님 요리 센스도 장난 아니네요.
Let's go.
갑시다.
Did we get too much?
우리가 너무 많이 받았나요?
No, this won't even last one week.
아니, 이건 일주일도 안 갈 거야.
Wung, I have to go to the bathroom.
웅, 나 화장실에 가야 해.
All right. We don't need anything else, right?
괜찮은. 다른 건 필요하지 않죠?
No, there isn't.
아니요, 없습니다.
Okay. Hurry and go.
좋아요. 서둘러서 가세요.
- Wung, my credit card. - It's fine.
- 웅, 내 신용카드요. - 괜찮아요.
No, I was going to buy today...
아니, 오늘 사려고 했는데...
to celebrate my raise.
내 인상을 축하하기 위해.
It's fine. Hurry and go. I'll wait outside.
괜찮습니다. 서둘러서 가세요. 밖에서 기다릴게요.
Go ahead.
계속하세요.
I was going to pay.
나는 지불하려고했다.
It's 182,840 won (≈$155).
182,840원(155달러)입니다.
Here you go.
여기요.
Sir, I'm sorry. Do you have another card?
선생님, 죄송합니다. 다른 카드가 있나요?
- Sorry? - It says it's over the limit.
- 죄송합니다? - 한도를 초과했다고 하네요.
Hold on.
기다리다.
Try this one, please.
이것을 시도해 보세요.
- One payment? - Yes. Actually...
- 한번 결제요? - 예. 사실...
Three-month plan, please.
3개월 계획을 세워주세요.
Three months...
3개월...
Thank you.
감사합니다.
Have a good day.
좋은 하루 보내세요.
I suddenly had a tummy ache.
갑자기 배가 아팠어요.
Are you all right?
괜찮으세요?
Yes, I'm fine.
네, 괜찮아요.
Wung, it was a lot, right?
웅, 정말 많았죠?
No, it wasn't.
아니요, 그렇지 않았습니다.
How much was it? Let me pay for some. I got a lot of stuff.
얼마였나요? 비용을 좀 지불하겠습니다. 나는 많은 것을 얻었습니다.
Yumi, do you know what money they use in Australia?
유미 씨, 호주에서는 어떤 돈을 쓰는지 아세요?
Huh?
뭐?
Australian money. (Pocket and Australia are homonyms)
호주돈. (Pocket과 Australia는 동음이의어입니다.)
Yes! One joke per day has succeeded. Let's go.
예! 하루에 하나의 농담이 성공했습니다. 갑시다.
- Give me a bag. - No.
- 가방 하나 주세요. - 아니요.
- Give me one. - No way!
- 하나 주세요. - 안 돼요!
Let's hurry. Hurry!
서두르자. 서두르다!
Okay, there won't be any spots left later.
알았어, 나중에 남은 자리는 없을 거야.
What's going on?
무슨 일이야?
There are so many.
너무 많습니다.
Let's stick it here so we can see better.
더 잘 볼 수 있도록 여기에 붙이겠습니다.
Everybody feels the same. I really hope it works out.
모두가 같은 느낌입니다. 정말 잘됐으면 좋겠습니다.
I'm so excited.
정말 신난다.
Let's get married and eat all three meals together.
결혼해서 세끼 다 같이 먹자.
Let's please put on a wedding dress.
웨딩드레스를 입으세요.
Gosh, these guys!
맙소사, 이 놈들아!
- Yumi. - Yeah?
- 유미. - 응?
Should we... do it?
우리... 해야 할까요?
It?
그것?
You know it...
아시다시피...
We're in the middle of washing dishes. What are you saying?
지금 설거지를 하고 있는 중이에요. 무슨 말을 하는 거야?
You said masks are best to do at night.
마스크는 밤에 하는 것이 가장 좋다고 하셨어요.
Mask?
마스크?
- Are you talking about facial masks? - Yes.
- 마스크팩 말씀하시는 건가요? - 예.
That really makes a difference.
그것은 정말로 변화를 가져옵니다.
You should've said that from the first place.
처음부터 그렇게 말했어야지.
What the heck? Kim Yumi, what were you thinking?
도대체 뭐야? 김유미, 무슨 생각했어?
- So naughty. - I'm not.
- 너무 못됐어. - 난 아니야.
What do you mean?
무슨 뜻이에요?
Come here.
이리 오세요.
♫ There's nowhere to go in this room ♫
♫ 이 방에는 갈 곳이 없어요 ♫
If I marry Wung, I want to cook a lot of delicious things for him. [Cook Cell]
웅이랑 결혼하면 맛있는거 많이 해주고 싶어요. [쿡 셀]
It would be so great if we lived together forever. [Housework Cell]
영원히 함께 살면 정말 좋을 것 같아요. [가사 셀]
♫ I'm in suspense. While I'm on my way to collect the heart I left behind ♫
♫ 지금 불안한 상태야. 두고 온 마음을 주우러 가는 길 ♫
♫ It's getting soaked. It's slowly closing. ♫
♫ 점점 젖어가고 있어요. 천천히 닫히고 있어요. ♫
I knew you'd look good in this.
나는 당신이 이것에 잘 보일 것이라는 것을 알았습니다.
That's too tight. I don't think my blood is flowing.
너무 빡빡해요. 피가 흐르지 않는 것 같아요.
Just hold on for a bit.
조금만 기다리세요.
I think my face turned purple.
얼굴이 보라색으로 변한 것 같아요.
♫ When the tireless rain pours again ♫
♫ 지치지 않는 비가 다시 쏟아지면 ♫
Don't make me laugh when I have a facial mask on.
내가 마스크를 쓰고 있다고 웃게 만들지 마세요.
Hey, Tinky Winky, let's take a picture.
야, 팅키윙키야, 사진 좀 찍자.
I don't want to.
나는 원하지 않는다.
Here we go.
여기 있습니다.
One, two, three.
하나 둘 셋.
♫ Soak up fall slowly ♫
♫ 흠뻑 젖어 천천히 가을 ♫
Can we marry Wung? [Anxiety Cell]
우리 웅이랑 결혼할 수 있을까? [불안세포]
Let's get married and do facial masks together every day. [Face wash cell]
결혼해서 매일 함께 마스크팩을 하자. [세안 셀]
Let's get married to Wung!
웅이랑 결혼하자!
I agree!
동의합니다!
A small wedding.
작은 결혼식.
Let's ask Wung if he thinks about getting married.
Wung에게 결혼을 생각하는지 물어봅시다.
Sensitivity, what are you doing?
민감성아, 뭐해?
Let's ask what Wung thinks about marriage.
Wung이 결혼에 대해 어떻게 생각하는지 물어봅시다.
Why?
왜?
Why? Should we not ask?
왜? 물어보면 안되는 걸까?
I think Wung would want to get married, too.
내 생각엔 웅도 결혼하고 싶어할 것 같아.
- Wung. - Yeah?
- 웅. - 응?
Can I ask you something?
뭐 좀 물어봐도 될까요?
What is it?
그것은 무엇입니까?
You know...
아시죠...
That is...
그건...
You know... ma...
아시죠... 엄마...
What?
무엇?
Let's ask Wung if he wants to get married. - Sensitivity Cell
Wung에게 결혼하고 싶은지 물어봅시다. - 민감도 세포
No! Don't ask him.
아니요! 그에게 묻지 마세요.
What's wrong with you?
왜 그래?
Ma what?
엄마 뭐?
Maha! Tari!
마하! 타리!
What are you doing?
뭐하세요?
What do you think I was going to ask you?
내가 당신에게 무엇을 물을 것 같나요?
I have no idea.
나는 모른다.
Oh well, then.
아 그럼요.
What the heck? Was that a new joke?
도대체 뭐야? 그거 새로운 농담이었어?
A new joke?
새로운 농담?
Reason, what are you doing?
이유야, 뭐 하는 거야?
Bulletin, let's clean this up while everyone's sleeping.
게시판, 모두가 자고 있는 동안 이것 좀 치우자.
Take off all the notes about marriage.
결혼에 관한 모든 메모를 제거하십시오.
Then there won't be anything left. Marriage is what everyone's talking about these days.
그러면 아무것도 남지 않을 것입니다. 요즘 다들 얘기하는 게 결혼이죠.
That's why they need to be cleaned up.
그렇기 때문에 청소가 필요합니다.
If we keep posting about marriage here, Yumi might make a mistake without thinking.
여기에 결혼에 대한 글을 계속 올리면 유미가 아무 생각 없이 실수를 할 수도 있어요.
Hurry. Hurry!
서두르다. 서두르다!
I got it.
알겠어요.
All done.
모두 완료되었습니다.
Please take off notes about marriage from now on. Got it?
이제부터 결혼에 관한 메모를 빼주세요. 알았어요?
But why? Don't you want to marry Wung?
그런데 왜? 웅이랑 결혼하고 싶지 않아?
It's not that I don't like it. It's not something you can do alone.
내가 그것을 좋아하지 않는다는 것이 아닙니다. 혼자 할 수 있는 일이 아닙니다.
Why? Wung doesn't want to get married?
왜? Wung은 결혼하고 싶지 않습니까?
That's how it was.
그랬습니다.
- Is that true? - Yes.
- 그게 사실인가요? - 예.
I saw it when I went to Wung's village.
웅네 마을에 갔을 때 봤어요.
Wung's desire to marry.
결혼하고 싶은 웅의 소망.
I couldn't say anything because I didn't want everyone to get discouraged.
모두가 낙심하는 게 싫어서 아무 말도 할 수 없었습니다.
But I think you should know. Notes about marriage keep on showing up nowadays.
하지만 나는 당신이 알아야 한다고 생각합니다. 요즘 결혼에 관한 메모가 계속 나타납니다.
I got it. But why was it submerged in the sea?
알겠어요. 그런데 왜 바다에 잠겼는가?
Then Wung doesn't want to get married?
그럼 웅은 결혼할 생각이 없나요?
I don't know why either.
나도 왜 그런지 모르겠다.
That is...
그건...
Just take care of the bulletin board, please.
게시판만 잘 관리해주세요.
It must be so nice.
정말 좋을 것 같아요.
Then how much of a raise are you getting?
그러면 연봉은 얼마나 오르나요?
I'm not sure yet. I'll look into it when I get to work tomorrow.
아직은 잘 모르겠습니다. 내일 출근하면 살펴보겠습니다.
I want to move to marketing department, too.
나도 마케팅부서로 옮기고 싶다.
Hey, now what fun would I have at work without you?
야, 이제 너 없으면 회사에서 무슨 재미가 있겠어?
You got Ruby.
루비를 얻었습니다.
Are you kidding me?
농담하는 거야?
I'll stop by everyday. Our offices are right beside each other.
매일 들르겠습니다. 우리 사무실은 서로 바로 옆에 있습니다.
Are you buying some clothes for Wung?
Wung을 위한 옷을 사시나요?
Yes. It's his birthday today.
예. 오늘은 그의 생일이에요.
Really?
정말?
How is it?
어때요?
This one? I don't think it's his color.
이거요? 내 생각엔 그게 그 사람 색깔이 아닌 것 같아.
Not that. How is it living together?
그렇지 않습니다. 같이 사는 건 어때요?
That is...
그건...
It's a lot more...
훨씬 더 많은데...
Horrible?
끔찍한가?
No, I like it.
아니요, 마음에 듭니다.
- Really? - Yeah.
- 정말? - 응.
I love it.
나는 그것을 좋아한다.
What? Really?
무엇? 정말?
Now that we live together, I think he's a better person than I thought.
지금은 같이 살고 있으니 생각보다 괜찮은 사람인 것 같아요.
Hey, then that should do it.
이봐, 그럼 그렇게 해야지.
Marry him.
그와 결혼하세요.
No. That's a no.
아뇨. 그건 아니예요.
What's there to wait? It's not like we're still in our twenties.
기다릴 게 뭐 있어? 우리 아직 이십대도 아닌데.
I'm plenty happy now.
나는 지금 매우 행복하다.
And his situation isn't great.
그리고 그의 상황은 좋지 않습니다.
It's Wung.
웅이에요.
Yes, Wung.
응, 웅.
I'm shopping with Yi Da.
나는 이다와 쇼핑을 해요.
Then when are you going home?
그럼 집에는 언제 가나요?
Yeah.
응.
But I might eat dinner with Yi Da.
하지만 이다와 함께 저녁을 먹을 수도 있어요.
Yes. All right.
예. 괜찮은.
What was that? I thought you're going before dinner.
그게 뭐였지? 저녁 식사 전에 갈 줄 알았는데.
- I lied. - What?
- 거짓말했어요. - 무엇?
To surprise him, even this morning I pretended to not know.
그를 놀라게 하기 위해 오늘 아침에도 나는 모르는 척 했다.
I pretended I forgot it's his birthday.
나는 그 사람 생일인 걸 잊어버린 척했다.
He's probably really mad.
그 사람 아마 정말 화가 났을 거예요.
Really?
정말?
Poor Wung.
불쌍한 웅.
He must be so sad.
He must be so sad.
I'll make it up at night.
밤에 해결할게요.
Gosh, you. That's really cute.
이런, 당신. 정말 귀엽네요.
- Right? - Yes.
- 오른쪽? - 예.
You're so deliberate.
당신은 너무 고의적입니다.
- That's cute. - Right?
- 귀엽네요. - 오른쪽?
♫ But I’ll hide it so you’ll never know ♫
♫ 하지만 당신이 절대 알 수 없도록 숨길게요 ♫
♫ Are you being nice only to me? Or am I misunderstanding? ♫
♫ 나한테만 친절하게 대해주는 거야? 아니면 내가 오해하고 있는 걸까? ♫
♫ I can’t figure it out, you’re making a mess in me ♫
♫ 이해할 수 없어, 네가 나를 엉망으로 만들고 있어 ♫
Happy Birthday, Wung
생일 축하해, 웅
♫ But what’s clear is ♫
♫ 하지만 분명한 것은 ♫
♫ Again today, you’re looking at me ♫
♫ 오늘도 넌 나를 보고 있어 ♫
All done.
모두 완료되었습니다.
♫ Are on edge toward you ♫
♫ 당신을 향해 달려가고 있습니다 ♫
Wung, are you off yet?
웅, 아직 안 갔어?
Yes, on my way home now.
네, 지금 집에 가는 중이에요.
I think I'll have to eat with Yi Da. I guess you'll have to eat alone. Sorry. 😭
이다랑 밥을 먹어야 할 것 같아요. 혼자 식사하셔야 할 것 같아요. 죄송합니다. 😭
All done.
모두 완료되었습니다.
Gu Wung, I guess he'll be salty when he gets my text.
구웅 씨, 내 문자 받으면 기분 나빠할 것 같아요.
I just need to bring out rice and soup.
밥이랑 국만 가져오면 되거든요.
Right!
오른쪽!
♫ Again today, you’re looking at me and smiling ♫
♫ 오늘도 넌 나를 보며 웃고 있어 ♫
♫ Are on edge toward you. I want to hear your heart ♫
♫ 당신을 향해 달려가고 있어요. 너의 마음을 듣고 싶어 ♫
♫ I’m going closer to you, ♫
♫ 당신에게 더 가까이 다가가겠습니다 ♫
He's coming.
그가 온다.
♫ close to you ♫
♫ 당신 가까이에 ♫
♫ I can’t hide my growing feelings ♫
♫ 커져가는 감정을 숨길 수가 없어요 ♫
♫ I think it’s time, close to you ♫
♫ 이제 때가 된 것 같아요, 당신에게 가까이 다가가세요 ♫
♫ So let me knock on your heart ♫
♫ 그럼 내가 당신의 마음을 두드릴게요 ♫
He'll come to change, then see this.
그는 변화하러 올 것입니다. 그러면 이것을보십시오.
And while he opens the present...
그리고 그가 선물을 여는 동안...
♫ you’re looking at me and smiling ♫
♫ 당신은 나를 바라보며 웃고 있어요 ♫
♫ Are on edge toward you. I want to hear your heart ♫
♫ 당신을 향해 달려가고 있어요. 너의 마음을 듣고 싶어 ♫
♫ Again today, you’re looking at me ♫
♫ 오늘도 넌 나를 보고 있어 ♫
Tada!
짜잔!
You're going to be so surprised.
당신은 너무 놀랄 것입니다.
[Endorphin]
[엔돌핀]
Is the setup going well?
설정은 잘 진행되고 있나요?
Of course, Endorphin can't miss the surprise party.
물론 엔돌핀도 깜짝 파티를 놓칠 수는 없다.
When Yumi comes out of the closet, we'll all shout together.
유미가 옷장에서 나오면 다같이 소리쳐보자.
Surprise!
놀라다!
That's too loud.
너무 시끄러워요.
Happy, happy birthday!
생일 축하해요!
I'm nervous. Why am I nervous?
긴장돼요. 나는 왜 긴장합니까?
He's here.
그는 여기 있습니다.
He's coming. He's coming.
그가 온다. 그가 온다.
Guys, when Yumi walks out of the closet, what do we say?
여러분, 유미가 옷장에서 나올 때 우리는 뭐라고 말하나요?
Surprise!
놀라다!
Here we go!
간다!
Ten! Nine! Eight!
열! 아홉! 여덟!
Seven! Six!
일곱! 육!
Five! Four!
다섯! 4개!
Three! Two!
삼! 둘!
One!
하나!
Go!
가다!
Surprise!
놀라다!
Hold on! Hold on!
기다리다! 기다리다!
Guys, hold on! We have an unexpected situation.
여러분, 잠깐만요! 예상치 못한 상황이 발생했습니다.
What's going on?
무슨 일이야?
What the?
무엇?
Did he leave? Why?
그가 떠났나요? 왜?
Is he really salty?
그 사람 정말 짭짤한가?
What is that?
저게 뭐에요?
Bluetooth mechanical keyboard
블루투스 기계식 키보드
It's a keyboard.
키보드입니다.
Hello?
안녕하세요?
Wung, where are you going?
웅, 어디 가나요?
Huh?
뭐?
Why did you come home then leave right away?
왜 집에 왔다가 바로 떠났어요?
I'm going back to the office because I have things left to do.
할 일이 남아서 사무실로 돌아갑니다.
But how did you know that?
그런데 그걸 어떻게 알았나요?
Are you home? I just left.
집에 있나요? 방금 떠났어요.
What is this keyboard?
이 키보드는 뭔가요?
You saw? It's a present.
봤어? 선물이에요.
- A present? - It's your first day at the marketing department tomorrow.
- 선물요? - 내일은 마케팅 부서에 첫 출근하는 날이에요.
That's the best mechanical keyboard there is.
현존하는 최고의 기계식 키보드입니다.
Famous writers all use that.
유명한 작가들은 모두 그것을 사용합니다.
My first day of work present?
내 출근 첫날이요?
I want you to write good things.
좋은 글 써주셨으면 좋겠습니다.
What's going on?
무슨 일이야?
Why are they like that?
왜 그럴까요?
- What's going on? - Do you know? - I have no clue.
- 무슨 일이에요? - 아시나요? - 전혀 모르겠어요.
I think I'll have to work all night so I just stopped by to drop that off.
밤새도록 일해야 할 것 같아서 그냥 들러서 갔어요.
I should be the one giving you a present.
내가 당신에게 선물을 주는 사람이 되어야 해요.
Give me a present? Why?
나에게 선물을 줘? 왜?
It's your birthday.
당신의 생일이에요.
Today?
오늘?
- Is it? - Didn't you know?
- 그렇죠? - 몰랐어요?
I didn't know. I totally forgot.
나는 몰랐다. 나는 완전히 잊어버렸다.
You remembered my first day of work and yet you forgot your birthday?
내 첫 출근 날은 기억하고 생일은 잊어버렸나요?
I'm kind of off these days.
제가 요즘 좀 쉬거든요.
When did you get home? I just left.
언제 집에 왔나요? 방금 떠났어요.
Hello?
안녕하세요?
Wung!
웅!
Come back.
돌아와요.
Come home and eat. I made you a birthday dinner.
집에 와서 먹어. 나는 당신에게 생일 저녁을 준비했습니다.
Happy birthday.
생일 축하해요.
You made all this?
이걸 다 네가 만든 거야?
I'm so happy.
정말 기뻐요.
Let's cut the cake later.
케이크는 나중에 자르자.
Did you make this, too?
이것도 만들었나요?
This is so touching, Kim Yumi.
정말 감동적이에요, 김유미 씨.
Thanks for the food.
음식 주셔서 감사합니다.
This is good. You made the seaweed soup so well.
이것은 좋다. 미역국을 너무 잘 만드셨네요.
- Wung. - Yes?
- 웅. - 예?
Should we ... get married?
우리... 결혼할까요?
♫ Like the star ♫
♫ 별처럼 ♫
♫ Always be at my side ♫
♫ 항상 내 옆에 있어줘 ♫
♫ Like a star shining in the dark night ♫
♫ 어두운 밤에 빛나는 별처럼 ♫
♫ always shine brightly by my side ♫
♫ 언제나 내 곁에서 밝게 빛나줘 ♫
♫ Like a Star ♫
♫ 별처럼 ♫
♫ while looking at me smile brightly ♫
♫ 나를 바라보며 밝게 웃어 ♫
♫ You who are so precious to me ♫
♫ 나에게 너무나 소중한 당신 ♫
♫ Always by my side, remain at my side ♫
♫ 언제나 내 곁에 있어줘, 내 곁에 있어 ♫
♫ Sometimes I sleep tightly curled ♫
♫ 가끔은 웅크리고 잠을 자기도 해요 ♫
♫ Hiding a lot of pain ♫
♫ 많은 고통을 숨기고 ♫
Yumi's Cells ♫ inside a lonely room ♫
유미의 세포들 ♫ 외로운 방 안 ♫
- You two look so close. - We just ran into each other a few times.
- 둘이 너무 가까워 보이네요. - 우리는 몇 번 마주쳤어요.
Of course I know. It's well-known.
물론 알아요. 잘 알려져 있습니다.
While you are working out, you catch someone's eye.
운동을 하다가 누군가의 눈길을 사로잡는다.
Have you eaten dinner? Should I buy you a consolation dinner?
저녁은 먹었나요? 위로의 저녁 사드릴까요?
I think there is something between Ba Bi and Yumi.
바비와 유미 사이에 뭔가 있는 것 같아요.
What is with this combination?
이 조합은 무엇입니까?
Excuse me.
실례합니다.
Hello. I'm Yu Ba Bi.
안녕하세요. 저는 유바비 입니다.
That action is a little weird!
그 행동이 좀 이상해요!
No! There is a jerk giving his jacket right in front of the boyfriend!
아니요! 남자친구 앞에서 자켓을 내미는 멍청이가 있어요!
♫ while looking at me smile brightly ♫
♫ 나를 바라보며 밝게 웃어 ♫